IKPEAMA JOHN CHIEMEZIEM

Electrical & Electronics Engineer

+234 705 642 7599



johnikpeama96@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/john-ikpeama



Federal Capital Territory, Abuja, Nigeria



SUMMARY

Analytical-driven graduate in Electrical & Electronics Engineering with experience in power systems integration, generation, transmission, distribution, management and maintenance. Enthusiast in the tech space, programming & the digital world. Experienced in project managing, a team player who understands the importance of hard work, communication, dedication, time management, and co-operation.

EDUCATION

First School Leaving Certificate (FSLC)

Mypa Schools, Minna, Niger state, Nigeria 2005 - 2010

• Senior School Certificate Examination (SSCE)

Federal Science and Technical College, Kuta -Shiroro, Niger state, Nigeria 2010 - 2016

• Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng Hons)

Electrical & Electronics Engineering
Afe Babalola Univeristy, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti state, Nigeria
2017 - 2022

Post Graduate Diploma (PGDip)

Project Management

The Chartered Institute of Project Managent, Ghana 2023

Graduate Diploma (GDip)

Health, Safety and Environment 1,2,3

The Chartered Institute of Environmental Health and Safety, state of Nevada, United States

2023

Diploma (Dip)

Facility Management 2023

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Electrical Engineering & Data Analyst

National Examinations Council (NECO), Nigeria | December 2023 - Present

- Implementation and process evaluation of new procedures or systems
- Analysis of data to evaluate performance of students
- Prepared reports and presentations to communicate findings and recommendations
- Involved in various software projects including web and app development

Engineering Intern

National Examination Council (NECO), Nigeria | December 2022 - November 2023

- HVAC Maintenance
- Computer hardware installations
- Server Maintenance
- Solar panel and inverter installation

Engineering Intern

Transmission Company of Nigeria, Apo-Garki 132KV/ 33KV substation | March 2021 - August 2021

- Routine switch yard inspections & maintenance
- Communication systems management
- Surveillance and Monitoring of the substation from the control room
- Grounding & Installations of Transformers including power, current, voltage transformers.
- Safety procedures and protocols at the sub-station

SKILLS

Hard skills

- Web Development (Full-stack)
- Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel & PowerPoint
- Graphic Design with "Canva Editor"

Soft skills

- Project Management
- Teamwork
- Time Management
- Leadership
- Adaptability
- Effective Communication
- Critical Thinking

MEMBERSHIP & CERTIFICATIONS

- Graduate Member, Nigerian Society of Engineers (NSE)
- National Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Nigeria
- Associate of the Chartered Institute of Project Management (CIPM), Ghana
- · Associate of the Chartered Institute of Environmental Health and Safety (CIEHS), United States
- Member, the American Academy of Project Management (AAPM), United States
- Member, the Chartered Institute of Contract Project and Facility Manangement (CICPFM)

LANGUAGES

- English (official)
- Igbo (basic)
- Hausa (basic)

REFERENCE

Engr.Dr Femi Onibonoje

• Provost, College of Engineering - Afe Babalola University, Nigeria

Phone: +234 803 844 8079

Engr.Dr Sam Adebo

• National Examination Council (NECO), Nigeria

Phone: +234 806 953 1521